<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Putty | Coder Blog VJIA]]></title>
  <link href="http://icersummer.github.io/blog/categories/putty/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://icersummer.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-08T20:44:03-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://icersummer.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vincent J]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[使用带有TAB功能的superPutty代替putty]]></title>
    <link href="http://icersummer.github.io/blog/2014/04/08/use-superputty-to-replace-putty/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-08T21:12:03-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://icersummer.github.io/blog/2014/04/08/use-superputty-to-replace-putty</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>设置中SuperPutty是依赖于putty的，需要设置Putty.exe的路径。</p>

<p>官网： <a href="http://code.google.com/p/superputty/">http://code.google.com/p/superputty/</a></p>

<p>下载地址：<a href="http://code.google.com/p/superputty/downloads/detail?name=SuperPutty-1.4.0.4.zip&amp;can=2&amp;q=">link</a></p>

<p>官方说明：</p>

<blockquote><p>Introduction</p>

<p>SuperPutty is a Windows GUI Application that allows the PuTTY SSH Client to be opened in Tabs. Additionally there is support for SCP to transfer files.</p>

<p>SuperPutty is written in C# and runs on any Windows platform supporting the .NET Framework 2.0 or newer.</p>

<p>Features</p></blockquote>

<pre><code>Docking user interface allows personalized workspace and managing multiple PuTTY sessions easy
Export/Import session configuration
Upload files securely using the scp or sftp protocols
Layouts
Supports PuTTY session configurations including Private Keys
Supports SSH, RLogin, Telnet and RAW protocols
Supports local shell via MinTTY or puttycyg
Supports KiTTY 
</code></pre>

<blockquote><p>Project Status</p></blockquote>

<p>SuperPutty is stable and usable. Please report and bugs in the issue tracker</p>

<p>来自softpedia.com的评论：</p>

<p><a href="http://www.softpedia.com/get/Network-Tools/Telnet-SSH-Clients/SuperPutty.shtml">SoftPedia.com</a></p>

<p>Softpedia Editor&rsquo;s Review for SuperPuTTY</p>

<p>EDITOR&rsquo;S RATING:   4.5/5</p>

<p>**Accessible and user-friendly PuTTY interface that features support for KiTTY, SSH, RLogin, RAW protocols, Telnet and local shell</p>

<p>Written by <em><em>Mihaela Citea</em></em> on November 28th, 2013</p>

<p>SuperPuTTY aims to enhance the capabilities of the PuTTY SSH and Telnet client by allowing you to launch it in multiple tabs. It offers you the possibility to easily manage multiple sessions of PuTTY using a single, comprehensive working environment.</p>

<p>Aside from this significantly important advantage, the application comes with all the advantages and tools that PuTTY brings. It features support for multiple connection types and protocols, including Raw, Telnet, SCP, Rlogin, SSH, Serial, KiTTY and local shell via Cygterm and Mintty.</p>

<p>The tab-based interface enables you to personalize your workspace and organize all the running PuTTY sessions. You can easily create a new session and opt for the desired profile to load. The xterm terminal emulator is intended for advanced users, while the comprehensive configuration panel of PuTTY enables you to change the connection options.</p>

<p>Various general settings are available for customization and the application enables you to configure line discipline and remote-controlled printing. Also, you can set keyboard controls, notifications and alarms, as well as tweak the behavior of the terminal screen, TCP connections, login and terminal details, environment variables, proxy settings and a few settings specific to each protocol type.</p>

<p>Sessions can be imported and exported and layouts can be saved for later use. The main window of SuperPuTTY allows quick switching between used protocols, hosts and sessions, as well as one-click configuration selection and command sending.</p>

<p>SuperPuTTY enables you to link your machine to multiple computers and control all the workstations using one single interface. Aside from running multiple sessions, it tries to enhance the power of PuTTY even more, with advanced support for data encryption, reliable command-line SCP and SFTP clients for file uploading, port forwarding and private key-based authentication.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
